Finding Aid for Radical Education Project publications, 1961-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Radical Education Project publications 1961-1969
Radical Education Project (Ann Arbor, Mich.).
[744] DA 2; R129; P976
1 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was accumulated from various sources.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Radical Education Project (Ann Arbor, Mich.) was an effort by SDS activists and intellectuals to develop a research, education, and publication center designed to strengthen the movement toward a new left in America.
The collection consists of pamphlets and publications of the Radical Education Project on such topics as imperialism, class conflict, women's liberation, capitalism, and the Third World. The collection has been arranged alphabetically by title.
Subjects:
Radicalism--United States.; Radical Education Project (Detroit, Mich.)
- Publications
  - The academic quagmire. Stu Dowty 1968 (Box 1)
  - African studies in America: The extended family. Africa research group. 1969 (Box 1)
  - America the beautiful: an essay on Daniel Boorstin and Louis Hartz. James O'Brien. undated (Box 1)
  - American economic imperialism. William Caspary. undated (Box 1)
  - Anthropology and imperialism. Kathleen Gough Aberle. undated (Box 1)
  - The argument of Latin America. Carlos Fuentes. 1963 (Box 1)
  - Armed struggle in Southern Africa. Africa research group (Box 1)
  - The black book. Earl Ofari, ed (Box 1)
  - Building Lyndon Johnson. David Welsh (Box 1)
  - Bus stop-Alice's restaurant revisited. George Hanley (Box 1)
  - Chinese aggression myth or menace? Charles S. Burchill (Box 1)
  - The common market, international capitalism and "supra-nationality." Ernest Mandel. 1967 (Box 1)
  - Consumption: domestic imperialism. Dave Gilbert (Box 1)
  - Contemptuous hairdressers: ceremonies of humiliation in school. Edgar Z. Friedenberg 1966 (Box 1)
  - Corporate imperialism for the poor. Richard Cloward and Frances Fox Piven (Box 1)
  - The cultural revolution in China-a socialist analysis. Leo Huberman and Paul Sweezy. 1967 (Box 1)
  - A divorce trial in China. Felix Greene 1961 (Box 1)
  - Students for a democratic society. ERAP(Economic Research and Action Project). Pamphlet and introductory article (Box 1)
  - Economic aspects of U.S. imperialism. Harry Magdoff 1966 (Box 1)
  - Education-An American problem. Bill Ayers (Box 1)
  - Exploitation or aid? US-Brazil economic relations. Andre Gunder Frank 1963 (Box 1)
  - The first street school. George Dennison 1966 (Box 1)
  - G.E. Profile of a corporation. Jerry De Muth 1967 (Box 1)
  - A Galbraith reappraisal: the ideologue as gadfly. Robert Fitch 1968 (Box 1)
  - The great Flint sit-down strike against G.M. 1936-37. Walter Linder 1967 (Box 1)
  - Guevara, Debray and the CIA. report from Bolivia. Richard Gott 1967 (Box 1)
  - Historians and the New Deal. Brad Wiley (Box 1)
  - Hunger. Andre Gunder Frank (Box 1)
  - Imperialism: an exchange. Robert Wolfe and Ronald Aronson 1966 (Box 1)
  - Imperialism old and new. Hamza Alavi 1964 (Box 1)
  - In white America-SDS & radical consciousness. Greg Calvert and Carl Davidson (Box 1)
  - Kennedy's Cultural Center is a leopard-skin pillbox hat. Charlie Simpson (Box 1)
  - Labor and the south. Black workers set against white-strike broken. Robert Analavage 1963 (Box 1)
  - Latin America. Decrepit capitalist castle with a feudal-seeming facade. Andre Gunder Frank 1963 (Box 1)
  - The law & monopoly. The case of Tetracyclene. Richard Goodman 1963 (Box 1)
  - The long March in Latin America. Guerrilla movements: Theory and practice. Regis Debray 1965 (Box 1)
  - The meaning of economic imperialism. James O'Connor (Box 1)
  - On the mechanisms of imperialism. The case of Brazil. Andre Gunder Frank 1964 (Box 1)
  - Mexico 1968. A study of domination and repression. North American Congress on Latin America (Box 1)
  - Myths of the cold war. Isaac Deutscher (Box 1)
  - Nashville. A preliminary study of the power structure. David Kotelchuck and Ronda Stilley (Box 1)
  - N.A.C.L.A. research methodology guide. North American Congress on Latin America 1968 (Box 1)
  - The new left. Greg Calvert & Carol Neiman 1968 (Box 1)
  - Peasants & revolution. Hamza Alavi 1965 (Box 1)
  - The political economy of women's liberation. Margaret Benston 1966 (Box 1)
  - The political economy of youth (youth as class). John and Margaret Rowntree (Box 1)
  - The position and progress of black America. Some pertinent statistics. Thomas F. Mayer 1967 (Box 1)
  - Power in American society. Jim Jacobs (Box 1)
  - The power of the poor. Warren C. Haggstrom 1963 (Box 1)
  - The powers behind apartheid. G. Fasulo (Box 1)
  - Problems of United States capitalism. Harry Magdoff 1965 (Box 1)
  - Putting-on the poverty program. David Wellman (Box 1)
  - A radical defense handbook. Movement Liberation Front (Box 1)
  - Radical education project. articles. 1966 (Box 1)
  - Radicals in professions. Selected papers. Radical Education Project. 1967 (Box 1)
  - The rise of the people's communes. Anna Louise Strong (Box 1)
  - Rostow's stages of economic growth through escalation to nuclear destruction. Andre Gunder Frank (Box 1)
  - S.M. Lipset: Social Scientist of the smooth society. James Jacobs (Box 1)
  - Scarce resources. The Dynamic of American imperialism. Heather Dean (Box 1)
  - A seminar on radicalism in US history. Ken Walzer & Dennis Gregg (Box 1)
  - Stock ownership and the control of corporations. Don Villarejo 1961 (Box 1)
  - The struggle in Guinea. Amilcar Cabral. Africa Research Group (Box 1)
  - The third world--its emergence and contours. Keith Buchanan 1963 (Box 1)
  - Thoughts on the movement. Who does the movement move? John McDermott 1967 (Box 1)
  - To the point of production. An interview with John Watson 1969 (Box 1)
  - Towards a democratic history. Jesse Lemisch 1967 (Box 1)
  - Trapped in a system. Carl Oglesby 1966 (Box 1)
  - The U.A.W. settles with FORD. Sellout and insurgency in the auto industry. Jim Jacobs (Box 1)
  - USA-the labor revolt. Stanley Weir 1967 (Box 1)
  - The university. Allen Krebs 1967 (Box 1)
  - The university-military complex. A directory and related documents. North American Congress on Latin America (Box 1)
  - Vietnam. A thousand years of struggle. Terry Cannon 1969 (Box 1)
  - Vietnam & the third world. Che Guevara 1967 (Box 1)
  - Visit to a rural commune. Felix Greene (Box 1)
  - Walt W. Rostow: the stages of economic stagnation. John H. Coatsworth (Box 1)
  - What is guerrilla theatre, anyway? Wisconsin Draft Resistance Union 1968 (Box 1)
  - Where it's at. A research guide for community organizing. Jill Hamberg with Paul Booth, Mimi Feingold, and Carl Wittman 1967 (Box 1)
  - White blindspot. Noel Ignatin; Can white workers radicals be radicalized? Ted Allen (Box 1)
  - Would you believe... ? An introductory critique of The True Believer by Paul Breines and Eric Hoffer and Cold war ideology by Peter Wiley (Box 1)
  - Zionism and the Israeli state. Larry Hochman (Box 1)
  - Statement of Carl Oglesby, President of Students for a Democratic Society. March on Washington November 27, 1965 (Box 1)